Lyla S. Taguma

(+44) 7367863686 London, UK

lyla.taguma@gmail.com

LinkedIn | GitHub

NEUROSCIENCE GRADUATE · ASPIRING FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Advocate of interdisciplinary collaboration & open-source software solutions.

Curious by nature, possessing a discerning eye for aesthetics and attentiveness to detail.

Passionate about crafting seamless digital experiences to practise UI design with improved accessibility.

Thrilled to apply skills & knowledge to address real-world problems in a creative & innovative environment.

Skills

React On TypeScript On Procreate On Bootstrap, Tailwind, SCSS On RESTful APIs

Node.js
 JavaScript
 Figma & Miro
 Bash, Terminal workflow
 Adobe Illustrator / Inkscape
 Next.js
 PostgreSQL
 Python / R
 Git / GitHub version control
 statistics, hypothesis testing

Other Languages English native proficiency

Japanese native proficiency

French conversational, reading & writing proficiency

Major Projects

Next.js Web-Application Personal Portfolio Website

2024 Vercel & React.js

London, UK

Built a portfolio (https://lysts.vercel.app/) in Next.js to learn the latest React.js optimisations using TypeScript,
 CSS, Framer Motion, Resend, and more. Includes a contact form, a simplistic interface, and subtle animations.

Undergraduate Research Oestrous Cycle Dependent Modulation of Cortical & Hippocampal Formation Activity

2023 The Rochefort Lab, Centre for Discovery Brain Sciences Edinburgh, UK

 Drove analysis and visualisation of brain activity data obtained using cutting-edge neural recording techniques in mice using Python. Collaborated & presented with professional neuroscientists, informaticians, technicians.

Game Development & Design Artist Role

2022 – 2023 Independent Groups (Ludum Dare, itch.io)

Edinburgh, UK

Teamed up with UX/UI/sound designers and game programmers, globally. Gained familiarity with FMOD and Unity. Used Procreate & Adobe Illustrator for art. Advised storyline and UX/UI changes to elevate product.

Treasurer (Executive Committee Board Member) & Librarian

2020 – 2023 Edinburgh University String & Chamber Orchestra

Edinburgh, UK

 Analysed and managed finances (e.g., tour expenses); brought a society out of debt during COVID-19, raising annual revenue by 6-fold over the last 3 years. Organised, distributed, and archived music score libraries.

HP Mars Home Planet Competition, Global Shortlist Qualifiers

2018 Hewlett Packard

Japan

 Conceptualised, designed, and nationally presented sustainable and energy-efficient transportation solutions for human life envisioned on Mars, in collaboration with Kaisei Academy (KIA) & Toshima-gaoka Academy.

Education & Certifications

Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp Full-Stack Development Course by Dr. Angela Yu

2023 - 2024 Udemy Platform

London (remote), UK

Practised full-stack engineering tools: CSS Bootstrap, React.js, JavaScript/TypeScript logic, design concepts,
 SQL/PostgreSQL, authentication, firebase, Git/GitHub, Postman/REST/APIs, and Bash. Certification received.

Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Sciences, Neuroscience Honours

2019 – 2023 The University of Edinburgh, College of Medicine & Veterinary Medicine

Edinburgh, UK

Certified in animal care and surgery. Explored biomedicine, biology, biochemistry, and anatomy/development.

Middle & High School Diploma, Academic Merit Award, AP Scholar Award

2011 – 2019 The International School of the Sacred Heart

Tokyo, Japan

Advanced Placement in English Language & Composition, Calculus AB, Calculus BC, French Language,
 Chemistry, and Biology. Awarded for achieving grades above A- in 70% or more of subjects taken. Awarded in Fine Arts for

Employment Experience

Freelance Artist & Composer

2019 – 2024 Self-employed Service

(remote) International

- Provided interface design ideas & graphical elements (e.g. favicons). Currently working on artwork for a
 podcast on addiction science and a start-up in protein research based in Seattle, Washington.
- Composed, recorded, and mixed for a film track commission for Bournemouth filmmakers using Reaper.

Academic & Fine Arts Tutor

2018 – 2022 Self-employed Service

Japan & UK

Covered a wide range of academics & music for youths with personalised action plans or violin/music lessons.

Instructor & Teaching Assistant for Tokyo Metro

2018 – 2022 Tokyo Metro

Tokyo, Japan

 Created interactive guidance sessions and educational films engaging Tokyo Metro employees in preparation for the 2020 Tokyo Olympics. Resolved nuanced English translation issues, improving customer satisfaction.

Financial Advisor, Marketing, & Personal Assistant

2019 – 2020 Tokyo Sinfonia, Internship

Tokyo, Japan

 Evaluated and identified financial shortcomings and long-term budgeting solutions. Secured sponsorships and strategised marketing via press conferences and social media. Tailed conductor in apprenticeship.

Translator & Editor

2016 BNN, Inc. Publishing Company

Tokyo, Japan

Proofread & translated 100 artist profiles for an illustration showcase book (English & Japanese).

Other Experiences

- Concertmistress, Co-leader, Soloist, & Member of Edinburgh University String, Chamber, & Symphony Orchestras (2019 2023), KPASSP Honour Orchestra & Choir (2015 2019), Show Choir (2015 2019, Chicago Festival of Gold), Vocal Ensemble (Maastricht International Choral Competition 2019), Tokyo Junior Philharmonic (2011 2014)
- National Competition Winner in Violin Performance (Silver Place, AJAA 2015), Gala Concert Performer Qualifier
- Customer Service & Translator for International Diners Club Card Ginza Lounge (2019)
- Translator & Description Curator for Art Exhibitions (2016 2019)

Current Endeavours

- Self-learning data structures and algorithmic paradigms for modelling computational problems
- Expanding React.js portfolio website design to archive past projects
- Prototyping an open-source application with a software engineer colleague and mentor
- Experimenting with Langchain API
- Optimising terminal-first workflow & blog-building with Pelican & GitHub

References available upon request.